In the first lecture, what that we
covered is that large language models
are really good at solving natural
language processing problems. And
[snorts] I think most of you are very
familiar with using them in chatbot kind
of scenarios. But to make them useful in
real world tasks, they do need to be
able to interact with real world
environments, tools, and code and learn
from what they interact with. So you
already saw some examples of test time
compute and robust verification that
Asia covered in the last two lectures.
Now we'll build a little bit more on top
of that. Okay. So today's lecture we
will focus on three different papers.
The first paper will start with the
notion of tool calling and how can we
get the models to go beyond just uh
reasoning to also take into account
actions via tool calls. And the paper
that we'll cover here is called React
which actually was one of the first that
went around to combine reasoning and
acting in language models. The second
paper that we'll look into is RLEF or
grounding code LLMs in execution
feedback. What this will focus on is how
do you how do you actually do code
generation by using execution feedback
from like being able to run the code or
run the tests of the code. And the third
thing that we'll look into is uh
constitutional AI where we use the mo
model critiquing itself uh as a feedback
loop to improve the model. So all three
of those techniques are ways for the
model to improve itself. But what
differs in each of these techniques is
where is the feedback coming from? It's
some form of interaction with either the
environment or some form of critique
mechanism or grounding using what we
know should be the right answer.
So let's start with um
just uh let's start with tool calling as
the first abstraction.
So what React really uh tried to focus
on was this notion of when humans want
to go and do some action, they think
about it first. For example, if you
decide that you want to come take a
class, you think about how that might
actually help you. Um
[snorts] and uh what this roughly means
is that once you have thought about it
then you will have a reason to act and
then based on that action you might
observe that you have a new observation
about the environment. So like once you
come to the class you might decide you
like the class or you don't like the
class and based on that information you
come up with new reasoning. Maybe you'll
go do the homework and then that will
make you decide something else. So there
is this loop between thinking and action
that helps us function as humans.
A similar loop can be very useful in
terms of refining what uh language
models generate. And typically when you
look at language models um they have
struggle to combine reasoning and acting
by themselves as isolated processes. In
today's models the reasoning has become
innate because thinking has become part
of the models. But if you look at the
history of the LMS in the last couple of
years this was not something that came
out of the box. And one of the
challenges of why it was hard for models
to combine reasoning and acting is
because they typically will hallucinate.
They will have no context of what is
actually happening in the environment.
So for example, if you were to type into
a model like Gemini or Chad GPT or
claude um what is the temperature uh
today? What is where where is something
happening today? It has no information
about the current events unless it
actually goes and does a search call and
then fetches that information. So it has
no notion of grounding in the real
world. And as a result of that, it
cannot go and take actions and then
actually uh combine that back into
reasoning. So React was one of the first
abstractions that tried to combine it in
a way that would be effective. And and
what you see today's models do is
actually go beyond React to do this in
in the chain of thought. itself. So
let's take a look at what we covered in
lecture one. So if you look at chain of
thought by itself, chain of thought
already gives the model some sense of
reasoning. So if you gave it a math
problem, the model will show the steps
the intermediate steps it takes to get
to the answer. But these steps may or
may not be grounded because they don't
they are based on model's internal
state. They have no feedback from the
external world. And then there is a
second class of uh LMS that were
developed for example web GBT which go
and interact with say web browsers and
what they're basically learning is how
to interact with web browsers or which
is a form of a tool. So they don't
necessarily have a reasoning process but
they're basically learning how to go
interact with uh web browsers. So you
basically can fine-tune on traces that
are uh interaction traces with web
browsers and then what do humans prefer
and not. But as a result of those two
different things, one is focused more on
reasoning and one is focused more on
actions. How do we combine these two
paradigms where we can both reason and
act in an uh in a useful way? A very
simple abstraction that React came up
with was uh just using prompting you can
get the model to generate verbal
reasoning traces. So first you say okay
I want to want the model to go do this
task and ask the model to think say step
by step about it and then it comes back
with its reasoning trace. You append
that in the prompt and then you say okay
what action should be taken based on
that and then you go take an action.
This really helps the model improve
performance where grounding matters. So
hotspot QA for example is a question
answering task. Then fever is a
fact-checking task. So these require
real world knowledge. They require
knowledge about what is happening in the
world. And then web shop for example is
an task where you're supposed to uh ask
the model to go buy products on the
internet. So it's supposed to do a
series of tool calls to actually
identify what product to search and then
have sequence of those actions to
actually complete the purchase for the
user. So each of these tasks requires
some notion of grounding in the real
world and without that grounding um it's
not possible for the model to keep
making progress. A second benefit of
having uh the model explicitly do
reasoning and action steps is that it
will allow the model to give traces that
are more interpretable. And
interpretable allows um humans to like
really trust the model's responses. It's
almost like getting the model to break
down uh what it's doing step by step.
So what you might be familiar with is
that if you prompt the LLM and you ask
it to think step by step which we were
showing in uh earlier uh examples then
you will get some form of a reasoning
trace where it shows its intermediate
steps and then if you ask the model to
say do a tool call like go search for
example um Google or find the
temperature it will go call an API and
it will get a bunch of observations. So
that would be action only. Um typically
you will have a list of actions if you
have a give uh if you have a list of two
calls that you are valid. What react
does is it will take a goal and have
some form of reasoning. So that will be
the left loop and then based on those
reasoning chains it will go and act that
will be the loop in the right.
So what what this is setting up is a
full agent in in itself where you have
some observations about the world and
then some set of actions based on what's
the context and if you were to for
example take this entire context with
observations and the set of actions that
have happened in the past typically you
could go learn a policy but that would
like require a full loop of which will
be complex and expensive but you can
actually start doing this in language
space which is what react is doing where
it's basically just generating the
thoughts in the language space and those
thoughts are not affecting the
environment and then based on those
thoughts it's then going and taking an
action just in the prompting space. So a
very simple abstraction of how to prompt
the models to start thinking about these
things and and and generate uh actions
which are valid. One interesting concept
I'll mention here is that when you get
the models to generate actions uh in
this particular slide typically how do
you know that these actions are valid?
So one typical way in which you get
these models to generate um correct
actions is to give them uh more uh to
frame the problem more as a
classification task. So you say that
this is the valid subset of actions and
then use that as a way to say okay here
is your reasoning here's the state of
the world and here is what are the valid
set of actions to go take next and then
based on that it goes and decides okay
this is the action to take and then that
generally provides a more grounded
response and in fact this was also used
in another paper that uh we worked on in
collaboration at Google with robotics
folks where the state of the world and
all of that requires very valid action
so you can't really operate uh without
having a list of actions. So that
provides one way to like really grounded
knowledge and what actions to take next.
[snorts] Okay. So in terms of
implementing this idea and uh in a very
simple way this was done uh with uh this
is this is an older model but with the
pal model with a frozen LLM in few short
examples the model was given some
actions some thoughts and some
observations and then asked to go take
the next action. So for the reasoning
traces, it was basically seeing actions
and thoughts. I'll show you an example.
And for the decision tasks, it it was
basically looking at what's the state of
the world, what is the thinking and then
deciding whether to reason and whether
to take action next. So you can either
go and reason or you can decide whether
I have to reason or take action next. So
let's look through an example and walk
through it carefully. So this is uh like
aside from the Apple remote, what other
device can control the program Apple
report uh remote was originally designed
to interact with? So this is basically a
question from hot pot QA. If you
basically just do standard prompting,
the answer that will come back will not
be correct. Now you can do chain of
thought where you basically ask the
model to go things step by step. It's
showing you all the intermediate steps
here. However, um the answer is still
not coming out to be completely correct.
Um
now let's see if we ask it to take some
actions where it can like do some
grounded knowledge and it can call do
some search calls. So it goes and sees
that okay the thing that I'm really
needing more information on is Apple
remote. So it goes and does an action on
Apple remote. It gets some observation.
Then it goes and does another search
call on front row uh which is some text
that is there in observation one and
then follow continues to follow on and
then it's like realizes that okay this
is a discontinued something. So as a
result there's not really a good answer
that it can give.
Now how does thinking and action like
interle those traces help? So here it
thinks first that okay I have to search
for Apple remote and then find the
program it was originally designed to
interact with. So it first goes and
searches Apple remote. It finds the
information that it's a remote control
introduced very early on like 2005 two
decades ago and it was originally
designed to control the front row media
center. Then it thinks okay so I need to
search front row next. So it goes and
searches for this. It's not able to find
it. So then it comes up with a new
terminology called front row software
and then it searches that and it's able
to figure out okay it's a discontinued
media software center and then it thinks
about it again. So it's able to give an
answer based on that. So basically uh
the reasoning process is an abstraction
which allows it to come back with better
answer than just taking actions and then
coming back with answers in between and
and uh interlection
and the observation aspect is basically
allowing the model to behave better. Now
what is happening in the LLMs today
where for example if you go in the
thinking mode of say Quen or um other
models you'll see this happening
automatically. So if you actually turn
on the thinking mode in sequent models,
you'll see all of this starting to
happen because the models have already
been distilled on these kind of traces.
So like the thinking fusion stuff that
happens and several of the open source
models already captures this kind of
things. So they've already learned how
to do for example tool calls and so on.
Questions?
>> Yes. Uh how do you how do does the model
know what it knows like what to search
or when to search like clearly you don't
want to search on plus one but like how
do you determine search
>> how do you determine uh I mean here it's
searching and then it's basically coming
up with an obs like here it's getting a
feedback right it doesn't know what it
knows this is from interaction right
>> yeah but you already have been trained
on from roll with the figure page you
shouldn't need to search right Yes, it
does. I need to search. Yes.
>> But does the model know whether it knows
this?
>> So, so I think there's contradictory set
of opinions on whether the model knows
what it knows. Right? Like there's one
set of people that will tell you that
models are very confident in knowing
what they know. But I think the other
set is that typically if you were to ask
the model to rate its output of like
does do you know are you confident about
set output? Typically the models are
overconfident.
They're not well calibrated. I mean
that's that's a research problem that is
still being solved. So uh as a as
someone who's designing a application
what you are looking for is not so much
knowing whether the model knows what to
know but like getting the model to use
the right set of tools so that you have
grounded knowledge.
>> Does that make sense?
>> Yes.
>> With the react framework on the right um
when you saying with the left loop
>> you elicited the reasoning to then
append to original part. Yes.
>> Will it produce the reasoning of thought
one, thought two, thought three, thought
four initially and then it goes and acts
in each one or does the act influence
the next reasoning step?
>> Act it's interle. So it's thought one
then act one. So it's happening in an
interle fashion like thought one act one
thought two act two.
>> Okay.
>> Yeah. So it's basically each one is
informing the next. It's like it's very
much like the human process. you thought
about you're thirsty. So you basically
start walking towards the kitchen. You
get to the kitchen, maybe water is out.
So then you decide the next step based
on that and you so you think that maybe
you have to go to the supermarket to go
do something. So it's very sequential in
that respect. You can do parallel
sampling and all of those tricks. Uh but
then you have to explicitly design that
process.
Yes,
>> there's no guarantee that the surgery
topic should take so L
is contradicting the surgery.
>> That's a great question like if the if
there's contradiction between the
results then what do you want the like I
think this is this is a question that
the user has to decide like if there's
not enough uh consensus. So typically
one of the things that we covered in
second class was that um we can give
more get more confidence by doing say
majority voting right so you basically
say okay or or you have some way of
validating the answer before you give it
to the user so for the end application
what you care about is the answer is
valid so you need more guard rails.
Yeah. Yeah.
But hallucination with search results
can be controlled much better than just
depending on the internal state of the
model.
>> Other questions?
>> Yes. But like maybe this is like not
answerable but I was wondering like from
the I wonder if people have looked at
like the KV cache representation of like
the thought and versus like the
observation and see if there's any sort
of interleing like kind of patterns
between them
>> given that the observations are
generally given by the environment right
they are not generated by the LM itself.
>> Yes.
>> So I wonder if that there will be sort
of this kind of changes you know in
between
>> that might be your research project for
this class. There there are open source
LMS that you can work with.
>> Yes,
>> maybe it's just a termination like
technology detail but this is like the
action space of react frame where it's
like the actions plus the sauce. Why do
we just think of like sauce internal to
the policy model and I think maybe the
action is just like like search or
finish. Why why do we say like sauce is
also part of action space?
>> We're not calling it part of action
space. We are calling it a separate
thing. It's like actions are on the
right loop and the reasoning traces are
on the left loop. Right?
>> Oh, you're talking about this one.
Um so I think because the language
models are trained on language uh
typically they benefit from having the
reasoning tokens in the right
abstraction as a way to um output the
right action.
So so that that's that's the main reason
to have those tokens. I mean if you had
intermediate representations then maybe
it doesn't matter.
Okay. So let's take a look at some
results. So the these two tasks hotspot
QA is a multihub question answering task
over Wikipedia and then fever is more of
a factchecking task. The action space in
these two tasks are very much focused on
say search over uh Wikipedia pages or
looking up a certain string or or
finishing that like okay I have finished
whatever task I was given. The action
space is actually very simple. It's
basically simulating uh the human
interaction with Wikipedia here.
So the baselines here are simple where
you're basically building a prompt the
standard prompting that you uh will see
as like simple prompting no thoughts no
actions no observations chain of thought
where you're basically asking the model
to think step by step chain of thought
self-consistency SC stands for
self-consistency where you're basically
doing uh majority voting or
self-consistency both of those
terminology is exactly the same thing
and then ACT uh refers to like there's
no thinking in between you're basically
just taking actions and u there is uh
two variants you will see in the table
where you can fall back to chain of
thought self-consistency if react fails
after a certain steps and then this uh
if the majority answer occurs less than
half the time then it can like back off
to react so you'll see this in the
results so this is an example of when
they uh prompted uh this large model
what they found was that uh react
generally does better than action only
it did not always outperform chain of
thought uh which was interesting uh it
outperformed chain of thought in the
case of fever but in case of hot pot Q8
it did not always outperform but if you
combined this chain of thought
self-consistency with uh or either
fallback or the other way around then
you do actually outperform u the
standard techniques. So what that
roughly tells you is that there's value
in properly combining the model internal
knowledge with the external knowledge
and then using reasoning as an
intermediate way for the model to arrive
at the right answer. So basically that
allows the model to reason uh what is
the right and accurate information to uh
retrieve here and it's so and it's
basically showing that it's able to use
search as a tool uh to retrieve the
right information
and then another interesting aspect here
is that what this is saying is when when
it's successful what is happening did it
get the correct reasoning traces and
when it's failing what kind of errors
are happening so one of the things that
I want to highlight in this slide
without going through too much detail is
that in chain of thought hallucination
ends up being a a major problem a major
failure mode but in react you basically
end up having uh grounded information
and the model is more trustworthy
because it has access to this external
knowledge base so it allows it to um
make fewer errors because it can
successfully retrieve the knowledge via
search
and then there is some difference
between prompting versus fine-tuning
when you can fine-tune then react
definitely does better and then if you
can RL loop then it does even better
which we'll cover uh next week.
Okay. So then that was knowledge
intensive tasks. If you were to look at
decision-m tasks and this can be say um
online web browser experiments or say
robotics experiments or like gaming
environments where you we will look at
web shop as an example. You require the
agent to purchase a product based on
user instructions. For example, you're
asking um the model to look for a
nightstand with drawers and then you're
basically evaluating whether the model
gets to success when it's interacting in
this environment. It's a simulated
environment and then you compare it as a
baseline to imitation learning. This
just fine-tuning and then imitation
learning plus RL which is basically just
supervised fine-tuning plus RL. And the
results that you see here are impressive
in the sense that even compared to say
imitation learning or imitation learning
plus RL having the reasoning abstraction
with react uh you get higher score and
you get higher success rates compared to
what's the baseline here. So uh the
score refers to like in immediate steps
and the success rate refers to getting
to the to the final uh getting success
on the action or sorry the task that the
user had assigned in this particular
case. So, React generally uh outperforms
what was uh possible with just uh
imitation learning or supervised
fine-tuning before,
but it's still far below what human
experts can do. So, there's still a lot
of headroom compared to say human
experts as you can see like React just
gets 66.6 versus human experts get 82.1
in this particular case. And [snorts] a
lot of challenges happen with respect to
success rate which is lower because if
you get any of the steps right because
this is a multi-step process then the
errors cascade over time.
So we covered react first. Uh it's
basically a simple method that allows
you to combine actions and thoughts. But
one of the challenges with this
particular approach is that if you have
very large action spaces, then you need
a lot more um demonstrations and that
that cannot fit in context. And then
since you require multiple reasoning
steps, your inference costs will be
higher.
But overall, it's generally shown to
have better performance in question
answering, in facteing, and in decision
tasks. And then your hallucinations are
lower and you get better decision
traces.
So let's have uh a few minutes of
discussion questions. So what I will do
is I will ask the class to think through
these questions um and talk to the
person next to you um to think through
these questions and then we'll come back
in 2 minutes.
Let let's start with the last question.
Any takers for the last question?
>> By show of hands. Any takers for the
last question to summarize what you guys
discussed.
>> How how what happens if the environment
is noisy? If the feedback that you're
getting is misleading,
you can make it up on the go if you
haven't discussed this one.
Okay.
So if the environment feedback noisy or
incorrect, you can add another layer of
like reflection the agent to reflect on
what what the environment gives you and
then reason about that.
>> Okay.
>> Yeah.
>> I was thinking maybe it's important for
the agent to have an ability to
backtrack whenever something doesn't
make sense or or you know if it's you
know going through a a chain of thought
it doesn't fit anywhere. You may want to
backtrack.
>> Yeah, backtracking becomes important
because the noisy feedback might lead it
down repetitive loops. Yeah,
>> you need to fix
times and
>> Okay. Yeah. So better confidence
metrics. So like you need some way to
build confidence over things.
>> Okay.
>> You could uh have it perform like the
same task multiple times and take the
highest sample or whatever.
>> Yeah. Yeah, that makes sense. They
basically have better uh understanding
of what how confident the model is on
this environment feedback. Okay, good.
Um any ideas on the second one? So this
like react is one way you can think
about reasoning and actions. What other
cognitive mechanisms should we take into
account if we are building these
processes? Yes.
>> I mean humans like their condition is
very different, right? Like depending on
the task sometimes we rely on our like
our own experiences in the past.
Sometimes we think through things step
by step sometimes. So it depends on the
task that at hand that we do that. So
just relying on react and taking an
action like doesn't necessarily lead us
to the right place like sometimes we
have to actually think and analyze and
like do reasoning before we actually do
any actions. So I think what you're
roughly saying is that there is other
thinking mechanisms that perhaps are
worth exploring. One of them what I I I
would phrase it as task decomposition.
Maybe the task is too complex. So maybe
I should decompose it into subtasks
before attacking it with these kind of
approaches. Or maybe there is something
to be said about like having parallel
approaches to thinking which someone had
brought up here as well as to like is
this approach better is this approach
better and then having
>> memory past experience
>> have past memory past experiences. Okay.
So yeah memory is another aspect. Okay.
Yes.
>> Yeah. Um I I think humans also uh try to
fine-tune what is the ideal ratio for
reasoning to action. Like for some tasks
you might learn over time that it's
better to think give it much more
reasoning time before acting it out. And
it might be interesting to see if the
paper actually tries to train this on um
different tasks to see what is the ideal
um outcome to compute like ratio for
each tasks. That's a great point. In
fact, uh related to that, you'll find
that some of the models today overthink
because they have like really long
thinking traces. And yes, and u even for
simple tasks, you'll see them like have
very long thinking traces. So there's
definitely some interesting set of works
there of like how to how to get the
models to not think too much.
Um let's go there. Yeah. Another
interesting direction would be like uh
given the different model at the number
of parameters like maybe some model is
better at um being able to do the whole
like um tool calling or train of thought
reasoning or even delegating tasks. So
being able to do like based on what
models you're working with um splitting
those different tasks
>> almost like building a compound system
where you benchmark subtasks on
different models and then delegating
based on the strengths of the model.
>> Okay. Yeah, that might be another
project idea. Cool. Okay. Let's move to
the second pro second uh paper now. So
this one is called RLEF. It's uh based
on coding agents and what what it's
basically saying is that when you're
building coding agents, one of the
things that you want to do is give some
feedback for the reinforcement learning
loop and often times what really helps
is execution feedback where we can
execute and get that feedback. So RLEF
was one of the first papers that showed
that with execution feedback you can
actually get much better performance in
coding LLMs.
Um why do we care about this problem? So
how many of you use cloud code today?
Okay, that that's almost majority of the
class here. So I don't think I need to
explain that a lot of the engineering
and coding tasks seem to be have been
delegated to these agents. And the
[snorts] aspect that matters more in
building these coding agents to be
extremely strong is that we need to be
able to understand the user intent and
based on what the code was generated, we
need some feedback uh from the code
generated. So that there's a way to
iterate on top of that.
So what this paper shows is um basically
an end to end RL fine-tuning framework.
The actions in this particular case are
generated code and the observations that
I was showing earlier come from
execution feedback. Execution feedback
is test feedback. You're running some
tests and you're collecting output of
whether those tests pass or fail. And
you get binary reward based on whether
those tests pass or fail. And then based
on that feedback you can iteratively
refine in fine-tuning time um and decide
to make the model better based on that.
So PPU can be used for this kind of
approach.
The two techniques that this paper
covers are two-tier test strategy and
then hybrid token turnle level policy.
Both of those are very interesting. So
I'll cover the basic ideas here but I do
encourage you to read this paper very
very carefully. So the core of their
framework is an iterative feedback loop.
They're using both training time and
inference time execution feedback. So um
let me explain the training time and the
inference time feedback. So at the very
top in the purple block, what you're
seeing is that the model gets a natural
language problem description. For
example, someone asked you to say write
a hello world program. Then it generates
a code solution which then it evaluates
on some public set of tests. If the code
fails, the execution feedback is
provided to the LLM for another attempt.
And this cycle will continue until the
either until either the code will pass
or it will reach a limit of the number
of turns it's supposed to um do this
loop for. And then based on u this
whatever set of solutions it has
generated for passing solutions a
private set of tests will determine
determine what reward to give and then
that will be used in the PO training
loop with RL.
So what here is happening is there are
two fundamental phases. This is the
exploitation phase of RL where it's
basically exploiting um the current
policy through inference time feedback
loops like whatever policy model you
have got and on the right side you have
update of the policy based on the
execution results and this allows
continuous improvement for the model to
uh self-improve here. So let's take a
look at how this works. Uh you're given
a simple example where you're creating
code to detect say palendrome
substrings. Uh so that's what the
problem statement in uh on the top is in
the first turn it generates a basic
solution but the implementation actually
fails in the public tests and uh there's
execution timeout which is a simple u
which is a very common issue after
receiving this feedback the model
actually generates a better solution
where it does some optimization and now
it does pass the public tests based on
that feedback. So you see that yellow
block now it submits the solution to the
the private set of tests and based on
that it will go and try to improve the
model now that the solution is is
looking better.
One of the key aspects of u their
approach was that during iteration the
public tests will provide immediate
feedback and will help it do uh better
solution development. So but this is a
small subset for faster iteration and
this is basically allowing you to guide
allowing the model to guide and get
better solution while the private tests
are completely hidden during the
generation process. So basically this
separation allows it to like do u like
not go train on the public test but like
only use the private test as the way to
get signal and this is one way in which
the model cannot simply memorize the
test outputs because it's getting the
exe execution feedback. So this they
found as a very useful innovation um in
the self-improvement loop. A second
innovation. So I will actually not make
you go through the details of this RL
algorithm. This is basically PO. But the
one thing I want to stress is that when
you're in a language model space, you're
outputting tokens. So you're outputting
one token at a time. In the policy
model, they are generating code tokens
token by token. So this gives you final
control over the the generation process.
But when they're using the value
function, they're computing this at turn
level. So this evaluation or the reward
is happening over the entire response
and it's using the last token of the
prompt. So there's a single advantage
value for all tokens. So if you were to
uh match this to where we are in say our
RL algorithms,
this is closer to what GSPO would do in
terms of like giving rewards to the
entire sequence as opposed to doing it
uh doing it per token.
Yes.
>> At the first time, how do you where do
you get the public?
>> Um, it's a test set, right? You keep you
you have a set of tests that you're
keeping as public test and another set
that you're keeping as private test.
>> So, you have a question again.
>> So, so on the left you said that's part
of difference.
>> Mhm. By deference the user could give
like
all sorts of like program descriptions
right
>> this is for the auto loop right so for
example code contests
there's a set of tests that are combined
with code contest you have to design the
auto loop for the model to get better
you can keep some subset of tests as
public tests on which you will do the
inference time feedback and then some
subset of tests you can keep to train
the
Yes.
>> What does it mean for the test to fail?
>> When the test is failing, that's
basically saying that the solution that
the model generated is not correct.
>> Right?
>> The model itself evaluates that the
correctness or who evaluates the
incorrectness output.
>> Uh the the test the test output is fed
to the model like you have failed and
then that's what's that's the execution
feedback that's going into the LM.
You're solving this problem. This is the
output you generated and this is the
feedback you got.
This [snorts] is um shown in the example
that I was shown here like this was the
first thing this code solution and then
the public test failed. So you appending
all of this and then this is the
execution feedback and then you're
asking it to generate the second
solution.
>> I was just wondering like what's the
evaluation process of a fail or a pass?
>> This is an actual running of a test like
it's a Python test. It's a simple Python
function.
Um in your homework you will actually
not for code but for uh uh math uh for
any uh problems that you'll actually try
some of this out as like not execution
feedback but just like identifying the
error in the generated solution.
So why does this help or what's the
benefit of doing this? So one of the
things that uh this paper showed was
that on the y-axis is showing solve
rates and on the x-axis it's showing um
the sampling budget and uh this is for
two different sets for validation set
and for test set and even though the
results are a little bit older because
they're on llama 3.1 they clearly showed
that after RLE uh and training on code
contests which is competitive uh coding
problems uh you clearly get much better
results in terms of solve rate
U basically solve rate 10 at K means
that you're um you're passing at least
one out of uh you you have 10 solutions
generated and then you're passing a
certain number out of that. So the solve
rate definitely goes up with the RLEF
and the other thing to note here is that
this is log scale on the x-axis. So this
is like definitely improving uh with the
execution feedback. Now why does it help
is the other good question to ask. So um
the base models typically don't benefit
from access to just faulty solutions and
execution feedback. Uh what is really
helping here is the the fact that when
we are giving u when we are training on
code contest we are showing it in each
turn what's the execution feedback and
uh with that you're basically also
generalizing to all the other
benchmarks. So it's it's it's the error
in the solution that that's what's
helping the model uh start to get
better. And and this becomes really
clear in this particular example where
what they're looking at is number of
errors in turn one, the number of errors
in turn two, the number of errors in
turn three, and then the number of code
changes being made um and the error
type. And this is for a smaller model,
and this is for a larger model. So what
you basically find is that with RLEF um
you as you go about iteratively in turn
one and turn two and turn three you have
uh fewer wrong outputs and in subsequent
turns you basically start to repair the
output while if you were to
if if you didn't have this uh iteration
loop then you basically are u not making
edits that are correct. So effectively
you are leveraging both the fact that
you have higher diversity in terms of
the number of samples that you're making
but also your edits are more targeted
because you can look at where you made
the error and that's one idea that you
will use in in your homework problem as
well.
>> Sorry I missed this but with the
execution feedback does it also include
it includes where the the faults you
made the errors does it include any
suggestions for how to fix them? It's
just getting a sense of like this is the
part that given out
>> but the problems are very simple.
>> The code corners problems are still like
I would say uh not more than other lines
of code.
So they're much smaller problems.
>> Yes. How how is the binary feedback
enough to um create the like I I I have
a feeling that maybe this were like very
easy problems. So binary feedback was
enough but for harder problems you would
probably also need to have like the
error trace or other metadata to
actually know how to debug it more
efficiently.
>> That's quite possible. I think that
might make a very good project as well.
>> Yeah. Does this necessarily encourage
like correct accuracy at the first time?
I feel like reward is final reward for
like the final solution, right? Maybe
this is something encouraging the model
to just like
like just repair
like
>> uh what's the question there?
>> Oh, sorry. So, I'm looking at the
reward. Is this like binary cor like
corrupt or incorrect?
>> But the model has a freedom to just like
do model terms, right? How does this
method like encourage the model to get
it corrupt like problem corrupt in the
first turn? So I think it really depends
on the kind of error it made and I agree
with you that for more complex problems
as was brought up it is possible that it
will take multiple turns but if it was a
simple enough problem and um then I mean
if you remember there's inference time
feedback here also right and you're
you're appending what is the error that
it saw and you're allowing [snorts] the
public test to pass be before you send
it to PBO so to some extent it will have
had a few chances to go correct itself
Yeah, can we just like increase like the
number of turns to finish the problem
like in real?
>> Yeah, you can you can try all of those
things. I I think these are I mean this
is one abstraction of that problem that
I'm showing you and overall I think what
we want to learn out of here is that
um the the self-improvement loop works
that's the first thing that we're
learning and it can work with uh in
simple enough problems with binary
reward and then potentially I think the
question is through process reward
models versus outcome reward models
which works better I mean what you're
saying is that do we need to give
feedback at every single step and and
it's possible that that is what matters
asia covered it in cross class outcome
versus process reward model. Right? So I
think that debate is not completely
solved in terms of like in each domain
and each benchmark you might have to
make different set of choices to help
climate.
>> Yes.
>> Uh I might have missed this but why why
doesn't encourage generalization
uh because I think like isn't contest is
more difficult than human level and I
mean
>> that that might be why it generalizes
better. Uh and another is that like um
what about like super supervised fine
tuning? um would it be be able to beat
like RDF for example like is since it's
>> so supervised fine tuning or what always
matters right like supervised fine
tuning on reasoning traces might
actually still get you some of the gains
as you probably have papers out there uh
saying that but generally um the I mean
this is still a question up for debate
but I think with RL you are able to
solve slightly newer problems so there's
a little bit more generalization that's
seen but with supervised fine tuning
anything that's within domain will
definitely start to see value, right?
It's the still the same loss function.
>> But do they have an inflation of the two
tier test strategy? Cuz one way is we
can just have all the tests in
I think public and they run this loop
and then you do PO.
>> I do.
>> Right. So why did they do that?
>> What do you do the PPO on? um the final
result after the how many returns to I
>> uh I didn't see that application I think
there must be like some amount of just
like they wanted to use more fine grain
feedback than just uh the feedback of
the public test right so that there is
no leakage between the two sides
>> like why would you care about leakage
like
>> why would you not care about
>> I mean they split the test into public
private themselves like right
>> it's all it's all test right like it's
all in the training part of the model
>> so why When do you after splitting get
two tiers like can you still get
>> I mean in the auto loop if you're
training on the thing that you're
basically going to use as the the
feedback then that that aspect matters
right
to
>> uh we can take this one offline
>> yeah I think there's a little bit of
terminology get off
>> um yes in the appalation study I was
curious why our produces fewer raw
outputs but more like timeout errors for
Oh, because uh it's probably so it's
pure wrong outlook is because um it's
able to fix itself but then if it ran
out of time in I mean basically the the
test ran out of time because the
solution was still not correct.
Um a lot of this is very domain specific
also.
Okay, I'm actually uh going to skip this
slide, but I think the main main thing
that I want you folks to take away is
that there is a way to incorporate
execution feedback to uh improve code
generation as a domain and and
competitive programming tasks is one
place where it has shown promise and it
does generalize to other benchmarks in
the code generation u realm.
Um so let's take a look at say question
two and discuss that for one minute uh
and then um among your peers and then
we'll come back together as a class
>> any takers for this problem like the
codebase doesn't fit the context window
>> okay
>> so one thing I know is that some tools
what they'll do is they'll do something
uh similar to the previous paper we were
discussing where they'll uh think about
what information they need. They'll have
access to some search tools and then
they will continue training on that
until at some point they decide they
have enough information and then they
move on to like something like what we
are discussing.
>> Okay, that definitely makes sense. Uh
any other takers?
Yes,
>> I think we can condense the
the code of each document into like a
short summary so that like can keep a
summary of each document and then
together they can fit in the context.
>> Okay.
Any other ideas?
>> Yes. I don't know if this applies here
but uh like in a regular setting I feel
like you can do like graph factoriize
version of your code and then do a
similarity based on like what you can
find and then again do another iteration
on [clears throat] that like just simple
rag right
>> and then you can have like in the loop
like what he said about like verifying
and saying if you have enough
information and then
>> if not you can do that cuz in that case
like you can use this organization you
can use the things that you're
extracting and then come with the rest.
>> Okay,
so this this is actually the kind of
thing that actually runs in cloud code,
right? Like it has to go search for what
is relevant and then like actually apply
the code edits there and one of the
benchmarks that targets this is like SWE
bench. So all the ideas that you folks
have proposed in the realm of like
searching for something having some
summary doing some representation all of
those are perhaps the first step to
solving that problem before you [snorts]
now do the test like what what code
patch to apply and then whether the test
pass or not. So code monkeyy's paper the
from Aalia's lab also targets very
similar ideas here.
Okay.
Okay. Let's move to the last topic. The
last topic is constitutional AI where
we'll have the model learn from AI
feedback. And the thing that we're
improving about the model is it is
harmlessness or its ability to generate
harmless outputs. So it we want it to be
helpful but we also want it to be
harmless. So what happened with LLMs uh
when they're base models is that you can
give them feedback in a lot of ways. uh
a typical way to give feedback when you
are trying to build a chatbot would be
that you look at the outputs and you ask
humans to rank them in like is the model
output correct. So you show it like two
different outputs. You ask it whether
it's correct, whether it's useful and
whether it's specific enough and then
based on those human preferences uh you
can build a reward model and then you
can help use that to help clients. So
here is like uh Python fine-tuning with
RLHF versus just Python finetuning and
as you increase the model size you
clearly see better responses with RLHF.
So basically that's this whole notion of
like you can use um these preference
model these preference uh responses from
humans as human feedback to fill client
on the model. Now that doesn't scale
very well because uh if you have to
collect tens of thousands of human
labels that's extremely time consuming
and tedious. Imagine that you generate
all these model outputs then you have to
ask humans to like rate them. So one of
the very interesting uh principles given
that the models can reason was to use
this notion of constitutional uh that
enthropy came up with which was very
much based on human written principles.
So they basically used constitutional AI
or human written principles called the
constitution and then use them to
improve the model by describing what is
the desired behavior. So humans don't
need to be in the loop except to write
that constitution. And the reason this
notion of rules works is because the
models get better at instruction
following. So if you ask the model to
like format the the response in a
certain way, the model is able to follow
that instruction. or the if you ask the
model that does this response have this
particular behavior then the model is
able to actually answer that in uh
truthful ways that's what uh the
constitutional AI aspect will will be
able to exploit. So what constitutional
AI did was it came up with a set of 16
principles which they call constitution
and they those will define the model
behavior and they use that so these are
going to be the set of prompts which
will elicit uh whether it's following
the constitution or not and then use
that to critique the model itself. I'll
show you an example and then ask it to
revise its response. So you're basically
saying whether it's uh you're basically
using some red theming prompts. You're
looking at the model output you're
critiquing it. you're getting a revision
and then you're using that to fine-tune
the model. And so that's that's the
supervised finetuning stage for um um
constitutional AI. And then this is the
RL stage where you're basically doing
the same set of responses and then using
AI feedback to train a preference model
and then using that to train uh the
final model. I'll show that in detail in
just a second. So uh before we go there,
let's take a look at what might be an
example constitution. I will not read
this word by word but I'll show you the
basic examples. So the critique request
in this particular
box diagram that I showed you is that
there's a red triming prompt. The model
has an output and then the critique
request is basically asking if the model
output has something harmful or
unethical and so on. And the revision
request is basically asking you to
remove any of those responses. A second
critique request might be that does it
have any gender bias and um the argument
about why that might be having a gender
bias and then the revision request is
can you remove any trace of that and the
third one is more like is it
inappropriate for uh young children and
then what would it take for it to be
appropriate and then the revision
request is rewrite it. So if you look at
each of these, it requires the model to
be able to identify these behaviors. And
then the second thing it requires is to
be able to follow the instruction of
like now rewrite it with this particular
uh style or way or removing this kind of
content.
And then the the way this loop works is
that humans come in and set a right uh
write a set of principles um that will
be used for the self-improvement loop.
In the supervised learning stage, you're
basically fine-tuning the model on this
data generated by the self-critique and
revision stage. So the critique request
might as I showed you might be like
something harmful, something unethical
and the revision might be okay remove
anything that's harmful and unethical
and um just with supervised learning
with the number of turns you are able to
um like just with the number of
revisions the harmlessness improves and
the help helpfulness
u will decline if you just like keep
increasing in supervised finetuning but
overall the helpfulness plus
harmlessness will improve monotonically
because um if you're trying to get the
model to like u to a certain set of
fixed principles then it does become
less helpful is what they're saying but
overall it's more helpful and more
harmless together is their claim
and then in terms of the reinforcement
learning stage first they train a
preference model based on the responses
in step one and the constitution and
then they fine-tune the LLM to maximize
over this uh preference model so they're
basically getting the model to response
to respond to in a way that's most
thoughtful, respectful and cordial. So
this is basically the loop. So there's a
preference model that's being trained
separately with this constitution and
then that's what is being used to uh
fine-tune the LLM to get better. So this
is instead of the RL HF loop where you
had a lot of human feedback now you're
using this preference model which is
trained with the constitution.
>> Yes.
>> So like all constitutions maybe there
may be some amendments. Um if so how do
you make sure that uh you're uh
costefficiently updating the
constitutions for this model without
having to um train all over again and if
so how do you make sure that the u
previous uh rules are removed
completely?
>> So there's two answers to your question.
So one answer is that uh r af is
generally done as the last stage of a
model and typically uh post training
like like once you have a pre-trained
base model post- training has typically
been um much smaller percentage of
compute so maybe 5% and that happens
fairly frequently for models to get
updated so in that sense um if you do
think that the constitution should be
updated
that happens at a certain frequency. Uh
overall I think the question you're
asking is this notion of continual
learning and how do we get the models to
adhere to certain behavior. I think
that's an open research problem at this
point in time like how do we get the
models to forget certain set of
knowledge or to adhere to like a new set
of knowledge or to follow a new set of
rules. So [snorts] that's definitely
something there are interesting answers
to that problem where you can like do
some cancelling of like getting it to
forget a certain set of knowledge by
looking at say interpretability methods
and so on of like can you cancel that
knowledge but then it's not proven that
you can get the models to forget
something.
So in terms of uh how this scales so
this is the number of training sequences
they're using and on the x-axis they're
showing the score of helpfulness elo
means that humans prefer it in terms of
helpfulness and then similarly on the
right side they're showing harmlessness
elo where the the humans prefer it in
terms of it being more harmless. So now
that we have replaced human preferences
with AI feedback, we're comparing it to
say uh just using helpfulness based RLHF
or helpful plus harmlessness based RLHF
which is all human feedback based and
then just using constitutional AI and
constitutional AI with chain of thought.
And what they roughly show is that just
getting the model to evaluate its
responses based on these principles, you
still get the model to be equally
helpful, maybe a little bit less
helpful, but it's much less harmless as
a result. So the harmlessness scores are
much higher [snorts] and that was
something that uh Claude and um the
claude models were extremely strong at.
And now that's that's a set of
techniques that used across the models.
>> Yes.
Say that again.
>> The chain the chain of sound has lower
health.
>> Uh yes without
compar
means that chain of sound actually
worse.
>> A possible that's a good point.
>> I mean you on the right.
So I think I think the correlation is
less with chain of thought and more with
the fact that as we as I showed you in
the last slide um
this one like anytime harmless is going
up there is some amount of like inverse
relationship between these two. So um
it's almost like
uh in this particular case if it was
more harmless then it does hurt the
helpful lens but overall you have to
find the right balance between these
two.
>> Yes. go back to like step one of like
the constitution AI to the supervised
learning part.
>> Okay.
>> So like it said in the slides that like
we want to fine tune on like the data
generated by self critique and repeat
issues. Yeah. So like I want to
understand like whether this just simply
means that we want to just reinforce the
lock likelihoods over like literally
like the generations like the robots of
like the of like the original policy
like you know when so basically we just
ask it to critique itself then we just
like fine-tune like this kind of like
sample robots so that they're more
likely. That's like what this stage is
basically doing. That's basically what
it's it's it's uh it's a stage that's
used in a lot of uh lot of other things
that you'll see but what this is
basically is doing a set of these are
kind of traces that it's generated like
it's based on reasoning you wanted to
follow certain set of principles and
then it critiqued itself it revised
itself and it got fine-tuned on that
these set of traces right I mean if you
were training it for thinking for
example these would be the reasoning
traces right so being being trained on
it's being fine tuned on those reasoning
traces.
>> But I guess like it's kind of
interesting that like there's not really
like explicit feedback, right?
>> There's no feedback,
>> right? Because it's just asked to like
do this thing and then we just fine tune
it over like what it has tried to do,
right? Then
>> yeah, but as long as the fine tuning is
not very large scale. It's like much
smaller than what the base model was
initially trained on, it will not lose
its initial capabilities, but the
distribution of what it will output will
start to get biased towards these set of
responses.
So the validation is feedback
um the AI feedback.
>> Yes. How do they validate whether or not
they provide accurate feedback or
>> that's a good question. So I think uh
for the preference model when you do
train this preference model you want to
have some sort of test set or validation
set to make sure that the preference
model will do a great job. So you do
want to have some human like typically
what you'll do is you will do a lot of
AI feedback but for the prevalence model
you'll also like get it to give some
scores on set of things and then match
it with humans. So you do want to do
some sort of like consistency with
humans for the preference model.
It's not like
>> it's not scaled to 10,000 or or that
level. You're basically able to do based
on compositional principles, right?
So overall in terms of results uh what
this roughly means is that if you were
to plot the harmlessness ELO on y-axis
and the helpfulness ELO on x-axis the
pre-trained base model is basically the
raw base model. So it will uh have a
certain set of scores uh but which which
are not very high. But with standard
standard RLHF you will if you were doing
that with just helpful only you will
start to push that frontier towards
getting higher scores on helpfulness.
And then if you start to make it helpful
plus harmless that that's what the
orange curve shows you. But then if you
do constitutional supervised learning
then you're still worse than doing RLHF.
But when you do constitutional RL with
chain of thought that's where you get
the frontier in terms of uh like the
best parto frontier in terms of
trade-off between harmlessness and
helpfulness. So that that's one of the
key ideas of this paper as to like you
can strike the right predictor frontier
between helpfulness and harmlessness. In
this particular case, if you were to
generalize the set of ideas across I
mean generally anything you want to do
in instruction following um where you
want the model to follow a sub subset of
instructions but they might be
conflicting then this style of
principles applies.
And some follow-on work that um went and
built on top of that includes the fact
that there was another work that tried
to compare RLIF with RLHF. There was
self-refin where it talked about
iterative refinements with self
feedback. One comment that's worth uh
noting here is that often times getting
the model to critique itself can be
harder. So having a consensus of other
models to critique the models sometimes
works better because the models might be
overconfident in know uh in not knowing
what they know. Uh and then there was
another paper that tried to like teach
models to self-correct reinforcement
learning. So this is an active area of
research and just trying to get the
models to be better at selfcorrection
um just beyond just the helpfulness and
harmlessness paradigm. So that might be
other set of project ideas that you
might want to explore.
So let's [snorts] uh recap um and then
um we'll have uh we'll close out the
class. So in terms of uh the react
approach, what we first looked at was
this notion of uh when we talk to LLMs,
we can get them to give model outputs
and what we wanted these model outputs
to uh be preferable by humans. Um which
is been a focus. But what React starts
to look at is this notion of can we get
the models to act in real world and
based on that feedback um and combining
that with reasoning we can get them to
be grounded so they can give better
answers to questions can check facts
better or if they if we put these LLMs
as decision makers in say game gaming
environments or in other environments
related to say web browser agents and so
on then they can make useful decisions
and one interesting aspect of like doing
it in the react style and language space
ends up being that the uh decision
traces are extremely interpretable.
There's several works on top of that
that try to combine this reasoning and
acting in different ways um and and
trying trying to get the models to do
better tool calling to the point where
like this tool calling is kind of innate
in several models that are out of the
box today. But this is kind of the
building block of how to get the
language models to to combine reasoning
and acting. A second aspect that we
covered today was this notion of RLEF.
So in in coding agents getting the
models to act in the correct way
requires some form of execution feedback
and you want to iteratively incorporate
that feedback so that you can do the
generate the right code solutions for
code. One of the best ways to get
execution feedback ends up being tests
uh unit tests. So that that's one way uh
the models have been used to uh
self-improve and um just this also
reduces the amount of budget you need to
get the models to get better at and get
state-of-the-art performance in say code
contests and other competitive
programming tasks. So that's one aspect
of just uh getting execution feedback in
the coding domain. And then finally what
we covered was this notion of
constitutional AI where we are getting
the model to follow a set of
constitutions which is a set of
principles written by humans to generate
feedback for self-improvement.
In general you can also generalize it to
anything where you can get the model to
follow a set of rules and then based on
whether it's following the rules well or
not you can get a self-improvement loop
going. So hopefully with these set of
papers you uh got a sense of like how we
can build a feedback loop on top of the
models and when the feedback loop has
enough signal then you have a way to
improve the model beyond just um what is
the data it was trained on
and these were several examples of where
this has been shown to work well. Sorry
this slide was not meant to be there.
Okay so this that would be the end of
the lecture but let's take any
questions.
Okay, this is like a really um just
naive question, but are there like um so
so because like a lot of like human
cognitive thinking is very paralleled in
how we're designing LLMs. Is there like
actual um very like systemic research to
uh combine like cognitive behavioral
science with um LLMs or like how do how
do we like think of new procedures to
innovate like this?
>> That's a great question. Um
I think where we are right now um that's
what we are like we we're using
parallels from how humans solve problems
because we are in this um space of
reasoning LMS like we're in the but I
think at the end of the day um we're
still trying to solve the problem of
what would get the models to hill climb
without like explicitly
uh saying in words what's the reasoning
space right so um I think the the the
closed source LMS have done better than
just like saying that this is their
reasoning space in words.
So effectively what I'm trying to say
here is that you can do a lot of
techniques where you can be like I need
to think you I need to break down the
task step by step which is something
that Aalia presented in the first
lecture. I need to decompose the task. I
need to analyze the task and send it in
parallel loops. And that's kind of how
humans solve problems, right? But at the
end of the day, you also want to answer
the question of like can that whole
process of search in the reasoning space
be automated and is there a well-
definfined process to do that search and
if there is if the search space is well
defined then you can automate it. the
the challenge of why we're doing it not
in an automated way but in the in in
this like language space is because a
lot of tasks that we're giving to these
models is not in a well- definfined
search space. A good example of that
would be that if you were basically in
gaming space where the action space is
well limited and the search space is
well limited then you can define models
to go figure out what the search space
is and how to explore that search space.
But we are talking about experience and
like going and experiencing actual
environments whether that's search tools
or everything else [snorts] and so so
you have to collect observations there
and then use that. So that that's why
you're seeing this.
>> Um yeah so far we've been talking about
improving LMS through different
techniques. I wonder how those
techniques are transferable to improving
agents.
You will see that in some of the
subsequent lectures but um I mean all of
this what's your definition of agents
versus LMS?
>> It's basically uh some LM that are
interconnected and have memories and
sessions and can't carry all functioning
calls.
>> Okay. So I think this is starting to
represent what I would call an agent but
not with doesn't have sessions, doesn't
have memory but because one of the
fundamental building blocks of agents is
how do we get the LMS to respond in a
certain way. So this ends up being uh
very useful to understand.
>> Okay. Okay. So for like for like react
my understanding is that they have some
show what kind of
cause and reason
but but their relation show that it only
benefits certain [clears throat] domains
and then help versus other. So now that
we have the more like RL based post
training methods will this kind of
handcrafted
framework become also weak?
Yes and no.
The reason the answer is a yes is
because if you can define the search
space of like what to go explore then
yes. Uh no because defining the search
space for all tasks of like what to go
explore is not well defined. Like if you
wanted to do the task of an accountant
like if you wanted to build a finance
agent, if you wanted to build a legal
agent, what is the set of steps they
follow? That's very domain specific,
right?
But you will be just uh generating
tokens like toolk is also just tokens
right so you're just generating robots
and using the reward to super
>> right so I think you can in an
abstraction I can answer it as yes but
like the specifics still matter right so
the reason react as an approach matters
is because they are basically saying
okay I can reason then I can take action
then I can go reason I can take action
so it's basically defining the sequence
and the workflow if you remember from
the first uh lecture we that we defined
the agent we said it's basically some
abstraction of like how I would define
that workflow. So how I would generalize
the whole react approach to an agent is
I would say okay this is the workflow
that I need to follow to accomplish the
task that the user has given but the
workflow to accomplish the task is still
very domain specific.
>> So that's why it's like very hard to
generalize across domains for
everything.
>> Yes.
>> I have a question about the homeism on
page on slide number 12.
>> Okay. the methodology setup page.
>> Okay.
>> Um like one question I have like is that
like you know there like you know the
way that you define like C subscript T
like the context like is the context
just simply being treated as a state.
>> Yes.
>> Okay.
>> I mean the reason it's called context is
that I mean state in prompting is like
literally what's in the context.
>> No. And another thing is that like with
react, right? Cuz like react like it has
this thought and then there's this
action but but it seems like you know in
the formalism in like page 12 like the
action I suppose that action would
include presumably both the thought and
sort of like the because like since the
action from that thought would just be
extracted right you know from the output
of the
>> so in the in that particular case it's
it's uh it's being given the choice. So
it's basically either outputting a
reasoning trace or it's outputting an
action or and it's making a decision
whether to output one of those two. So
it's
>> Oh, I see. So the action the action can
be just like a spend on reasoning trace,
right? And then it stops and then like
invest another action.
>> Yeah.
Um this might be a late question but I
was just wondering like this hless have
certain features but like have certain
messes so we can like impose this
concentrations like instead of like just
like to like try to find the model to
somehow like improve the hlessness like
for example like can we directly
restrict
this can use like when they generate
[clears throat] certain methods to
restrict like um to research you believe
hardly
>> uh yes uh I think it's that is done to
some extent uh at the same time these
models are trained on internet so no
amount of restriction is really going to
like get all of that out
so it's it's a it's a game of like when
you are training on a lot of data
there's data
Yeah, there is definitely filtering of
data that happens.
>> Okay, if there are no further questions,
um we'll call it a close of the class.
Thanks everyone.